Choose a targeting strategy for your campaign
to help reach relevant customers at the right time.
Targeting is how you define the audiences
that you want to reach and engage
when you're publishing an ad.
The two most common ways to define an audience
when you're using sponsored ads
are keyword and product targeting.
Keyword targeting matches your ad
with the shopping queries that customers use
when they are looking for something online.
And product targeting matches your advertised products
or brand with similar or complementary products
in the Amazon store.
Depending on the ad solution you're using,
you'll have two options for how to set up
your keyword or product targeting, automatic and manual.
With automatic targeting, Amazon will use
our unique insights to match your ads
to related shopping queries and products,
saving you time in campaign setup.
Amazon will also provide you with recommended bid suggestions
to help you bid more effectively and meet your campaign goals.
We calculate the suggested bid based on bids
for ads similar to yours that won impressions
over the past seven days.
This can help speed up your campaign setup process
and ensure you are bidding competitively for placements.
You can choose to set one default bid
for your entire campaign or choose different bids
for targeting groups.
These are groups of search terms and products
matched with the product in your ad.
There are four targeting groups you can define bids for
in automatic campaigns.
Close match and loose match for keywords
and substitutes and complements for products.
After your automatic campaign has been running
for at least two weeks,
review which keywords or products worked best for you,
such as the ones with a high click through rate
or a return on ad spend that aligns with your goals.
You can use these high performing keywords
in your manual campaigns.
Manual targeting helps you to target
specific keywords and products.
In your manual keyword targeting campaign,
you can choose different match types for keywords,
broad match, phrase match and exact match.
These match types determine how closely
the keywords you bid on match the shopping queries
customers are using,
giving you increased control over spend.
In your manual product targeting campaign,
you can choose different categories or individual products,
giving you greater control over when
and where your ads appear.
For manual campaigns,
you can set a different bid for each keyword,
product and category.
Letting you bid more competitively on keywords
that perform well for you.
Again, Amazon will give you a suggested bid,
but you set the maximum bid you're willing to pay.
Within both your automatic and manual campaigns,
you'll see the complimentary option
to include negative targeting.
With negative targeting,
you can select keywords and products
to prevent your ads from displaying
when shopping queries match them,
helping to exclude irrelevant searches
and lower your advertising cost.
For example, let's say you're selling high-end watches.
You know that shoppers who are searching
for products like yours are not budget conscious.
So you may decide to select negative keywords like cheap
or inexpensive.
This will prevent your watch ads
from showing up in specific shopping results
and detail pages where they may be less likely
to lead to a click or a sale.
To help select these negative products and keywords,
review your search term report
to look for these low performers,
such as keywords or products that have generated impressions,
but no sales.
Again, you'll have match type options
for negative keyword targeting,
which are negative exact and negative phrase,
and for negative product targeting,
you'll have the choice to exclude by an entire brand
or by product.
Remember, to get started with campaign targeting,
we recommend that you run an automatic campaign
for at least two weeks to see what keywords
and products perform best for you.
Then take those high performing keywords and products
and use them in your manual campaigns.
Keep your automatic campaign running
to stay on top of shopping trends
and use your manual campaign to bid more competitively
and confidently on keywords and products
that are meeting your goals.
Both your automatic and manual campaigns
can be updated and optimized at any time.
Ready to set up targeting on a sponsored ads campaign?
Visit ads.
amazon.
com to get started.